Exercise 1-16. Individual Practice. Now, let's see what you can do with the same
sentence just by changing the stress around to different words. I'll tell you
which meaning to express. When you hear the tone, say the sentence as quickly as
you can, then I'll say the sentence for you. To test your ear, I'm going to repeat
the sentences in random order. Try to determine which word I'm stressing. The
answers are given in parentheses, but don't look unless you really have to. 1.
Indicate that he borrowed the money and didn't steal it.
I didn't say he stole the money. Maybe he just borrowed it. 2. Indicate that you're
denying having said that he stole it.
I didn't say he stole the money. That's not true at all. 3. Indicate that you
think he stole something besides money.
I didn't say he stole the money. He may have taken some jewelry. 4. Indicate that
you were not the person to say it.
I didn't say he stole the money. Someone else said it. 5. Indicate that you don't
think that he was the person who stole it.
I didn't say he stole the money, I think someone else took it. Six, indicate that
you didn't say it outright, but did suggest it in some way.
I didn't say he stole the money, I only suggested the possibility. 7. Indicate
that he may have stolen a different amount of money.
I didn't say he stole THE money, but rather some other money.